Guide to the Cormac K. H. O'Malley Papers AIA.019
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II. American Committee for Ulster Justice (ACUJ), 1968-1981
  - Subseries IIB. U.S. Congressional Hearings on Northern Ireland
    - House of Commons, United Kingdom: Debates on Northern Ireland, Nov 25, 1971-Feb 9, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Irish Government Positions on Northern Ireland (I), 1969-1978 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Irish Government Positions on Northern Ireland (II), 1969-1978 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Kennedy-Ribicoff Resolution on Violence in N.I. (U.S. Resolution 180), Oct 20, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Lectures: Northern Ireland and Congressional Resolutions by Cormac O'Malley, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - National Council for Civil Liberties: U.S. Congressional Hearings on Northern Ireland, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Newsletter: Campaign for Social Justice in Northern Ireland, Dec 1968-Jul 1972 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Operation Washington (Lobbying Efforts), Jan 1972 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Photographs: Rubber Bullets used by British Army during Bloody Sunday, Jan 31, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Press Conference re: Congressional Hearings on Northern Ireland, Feb 28, 1972-Mar 1, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Radio Talks on Northern Ireland and Congressional Resolutions by Cormac O'Malley on Fordham Station WFUV (Transcripts), Nov 1971 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Report: Amnesty International Report of an Enquiry into Allegations of Ill-treatment in Northern Ireland, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Report: Northern Ireland: Hearings before U.S. House of Representatives Foreign Affairs Subcommittee on Europe, Feb 28, 1972-Mar 1, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Republican Party Platform on Northern Ireland, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Research Materials on Publications and Organizations, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Testimony, Notes: Congressional Hearing before U.S. House of Representatives Foreign Affairs Subcommittee on Europe (I), Feb 28, 1972-Mar 1, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Testimony, Notes: Congressional Hearing before U.S. House of Representatives Foreign Affairs Subcommittee on Europe (II), Feb 28, 1972-Mar 1, 1972 (Box 10, Drawer 6)
    - UK Government Position Papers concerning Northern Ireland, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - United Nations and International Legal Aspects of N. I. Crisis, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - World Habeas Corpus, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Subseries IIC. ACUJ Research Materials for 1972 Congressional Hearings
    This subseries consists of research materials used to inform the ACUJ's testimony in the Congressional hearing before the House of Representatives' Foreign Affairs Subcommittee held in the aftermath of the Bloody Sunday shootings in 1972. Included are extensive newspaper clippings from Irish and American newspapers and magazines, transcripts of the Parliament of Northern Ireland debates (1971-1972), and statements made by individuals to the Association for Legal Justice in Belfast that same winter. Of note are the 1972 platforms of the American Democratic and Republican political parties with respect to the situation in Northern Ireland, position papers released by the British and Irish governments, the Amnesty International Report of an Enquiry into Allegations of Ill-Treatment in Northern Ireland, and press coverage concerning St. Patrick's Day in the wake of the 1972 Congressional hearing.
    - Government of Northern Ireland Reports and Documents, 1969-1980 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - "Northern Ireland 1968-1973, A Chronology of Events" by Richard Deutsch and Vivien Magowan (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Parliament of Northern Ireland: Parliamentary Debates Reports, Oct 19, 1971-Dec 16, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Parliament of Northern Ireland: Parliamentary Debates Reports, Jan 11, 1972-Jan 20, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Parliament of Northern Ireland: Parliamentary Debates Reports, Feb 1, 1972-Feb 29, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Parliament of Northern Ireland: Parliamentary Debates Reports, Mar 1, 1972-Mar 28, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Publications: New Ulster Movement, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Publications re: Northern Ireland (I), 1969-1972 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Publications re: Northern Ireland (II), 1969-1972 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Publications re: Northern Ireland (III), 1969-1972 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - "Some Facts About Northern Ireland" British Army Report, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper Clippings: Economist, Sep 14, 1971-Jul 7, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper Clippings: Financial Times, Jul 28, 1971-Jul 30, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper Clippings: Hibernia Fortnightly Review, Apr 1971-Sep 1971 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper Clippings: Hibernia Fortnightly Review, Oct 1971-Dec 1971 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper Clippings: International Papers, Aug 1, 1971-Aug 15, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper Clippings: International Papers, Aug 1971-Sep 1971 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper Clippings: Irish Echo, Irish Times, and International Papers, Oct 1971 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper Clippings: Irish Times, Aug 31, 1970-Sep 8, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper Clippings: New York Times, Aug 16, 1971-Aug 31, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper Clippings: New York Times, Sep 1971 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper Clippings: New York Times, Oct 1971 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings: New York Times Editorials and Editorial Opinions, Dec 12, 1971-Jul 25, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper Clippings: New York Times, Apr 1972 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Newspaper Clippings: New York Times, May 1972 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper Clippings: New York Times and Daily News, Jun 1972 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Newspaper Clippings: New York Times, Sep 1972 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Newspaper Clippings: New York Times, Oct 1972 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Newspaper Clippings: New York Times, Dec 1972 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Newspaper Clippings: New York Times, Economist, Long Island Press, Jan 1973 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Newspaper Clippings: New York Times and Long Island Press, Mar 1973 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Newspaper Clippings: New York Times and Daily News, Apr 1973-May 1973 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper Clippings: New York Times and Long Island Press, Jun 1973-Aug 1973 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper Clippings: New York Times, Sep 1973-Dec 1973 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper Clippings: Newsweek, Aug 1972-May 1973 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper Clippings: St. Patrick's Day 1972, Mar 1972 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper Clippings: St. Patrick's Day 1972, Mar 1972 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper Clippings: Time Magazine, Aug 23, 1971-Dec 18, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper Clippings: U.S. and International Papers, Sep 1971 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper Clippings: U.S. and International Papers, Nov 1971 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper Clippings: U.S. and International Papers, Dec 1971 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper Clippings: U.S. and International Papers, Jan 1972 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper Clippings: U.S. and International Papers, Feb 1972 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper Clippings: U.S. and International Papers, Mar 1972 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper Clippings: U.S. and International Papers, Jul 1972 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings: U.S. and International Papers, Nov 1972 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper Clippings: U.S. and International Papers, Feb 1973 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper Clippings: U.S. Papers and The Financial Times, Oct 1971 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper Clippings: U.S. Papers, Aug 1972 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Newspaper Clippings: Ulster, Feb 1974-May 1974 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Newspaper Clippings: Various, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Newspaper Clippings: Various, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Newspaper Clippings: Various, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Newspaper Clippings: Various, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Newspaper Clippings: Various, 1957-1981, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
- Series III. Publications and Clippings, 1959-1980
  This series consists of a variety of publications and clippings from American and Irish sources regarding Irish America, Ireland, and Northern Ireland. Of note are two folders concerning the American Bicentennial in 1976 and the connections between Ireland and the United States. The series also contains copies of the Hibernia Fortnightly Review, a bi-weekly publication from Dublin. Two boxes of publications related to Northern Ireland peace and economic policy (ca.1957-2001) were added in a 2015 accrual.
  - Academic Papers re: Northern Ireland and Troubles, 1963-1977 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Articles: "Books From My Shelves," series on Irish History by David Hogan in Sunday Irish Press, 1959-1963 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Articles: Insight Team Reports on Bloody Sunday from the Irish Times, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Articles: Irish in America, 1972-1976 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Articles: Northern Ireland: Irish Papers, 1972-1981 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Articles: Northern Ireland and Troubles, 1963-1976 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Articles: "Perilous Days" by Michael O'Halloran, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - British Information Service (NYC) Northern Ireland: Summary of White Paper on Constitutional Proposals, 1971-1973 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - "Focus: The Irish Questions" by Gearoid Baireid, JD and Liam O'Murcada, MA, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Fortnight: An Independent Review for Northern Ireland, Sep 6, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - "Justice Denied: A Challenge to Lord Widgery's Report on Bloody Sunday", May 1972 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Triumph: Northern Ireland and Troubles, 1972-1974 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Arms Trial in Dublin - Irish Press, Irish Times, Fall 1970 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Cultural, Political, Sports from Irish Press and Others, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Cultural, Political, Sports from Irish Press and Others, 1960-1961 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Cultural, Political, Sports from Irish Press and Others, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Cultural, Political, Sports from Irish Press and Others, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Cultural, Political, Sports from Irish Press and Others, 1965-1967 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Cultural, Political, Sports from Irish Press and Others, 1969-1978 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Ireland and Culture: U.S. Papers, 1970-1975 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Irish and American Connections, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Northern Ireland: Irish Times, Irish Press, Independent, 1977-1980 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Northern Ireland and Troubles: U.S. Papers, 1972-1979 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Publications re: Human and Civil Rights in Northern Ireland, 1969-1973 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Hibernia Fortnightly Review: Vol. 36, Nos. 1-21 (3 folders), Jan 7, 1972-Dec 15, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
  - Hibernia Fortnightly Review: Vol. 37, Nos. 1-15, Vol. 38, Nos. 15, 19 (3 folders), Jan 5, 1973-Sep 21, 1973, Sep 13, 1974, Nov 8, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
  - Hibernia Fortnightly Review: Vol. 40, Nos. 14 - 25 (Missing 13, 24), Vol. 41, Nos. 1-29 (Missing 5, 7-8, 10, 15,19,21-28) 3 folders, Jun 18, 1976-Dec 16, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 1-3)
  - Hibernia Weekly: Vol. 42, Nos. 1-15 (Missing 3,7,11,14), Vol. 43, Nos. 16-30, Vol. 44, Nos. 1-8 (4 folders), Jan 6, 1978-Apr 12, 1978, Apr 19, 1979-Aug 2, 1979, Jan 3, 1980-Feb 21, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 1-4)
  - Hibernia Weekly: Vol. 44, Nos. 10 - 42 (Missing 11, 16-18,34) (4 folders), Mar 6, 1980-Oct 16, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 1-4)
  - Northern Ireland policy publications, 1957-1999 (Box 22, Folder 1-7)
  - Northern Ireland agreement publications, 1972-2001 (Box 23, Folder 1-12)
- Series IV. Ephemera, 1930-2000
  This series consists of posters and two scrapbooks that O'Malley acquired or created. One scrapbook, assembled by James A. Healy in 1957, relates to James Brendan Connolly (1868-1957), a South Boston athlete who competed and won at the 1896 Olympics. The other scrapbook focuses on William Butler Yeats and the Sligo Museum, also with a connection to Healy. The posters in this series announce various musical, political, and cultural events beginning in the 1980s.
  - James B. Connolly Scrapbook, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - William Butler Yeats and the Sligo Museum Scrapbook, 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Posters (events), 1987-2000, undated (Box 20)
  - 45 record from Box 6, folder 4: Songs: Jackets Green, Shule Arron, artist: Mary O'Dowd, Irish Pavilion Records, 130 E 57th St, New York., 1975 (Box 20)
  - Programs: St. John's Teachers College Fall Dance, Nov. 30, 1940; Gloucester School of the Little Theatre 11th Season, Rocky Neck, Gloucester, MA, 1930, 1930-1940 (Box 20)